Guide to photograph album Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus and Turkey - A.P.H. Hotz AD.MC.061
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- A view of the Armenian cemetery in Jolfa, Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref47; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Cemeteries; Mountains/Hills; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tombs/Mausoleums; Landscapes
- Three tombstones in the Armenian cemetery in Jolfa, Isfahan, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref48; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Cemeteries; Tombs/Mausoleums; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- A view of Sultanabad, Iran, taken from the government house (note: there are numerous locations named Sultanabad/Soultanabad in Iran. Considering the route, this is likely to be Arak (formerly called Soltan-Abad))., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref49; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Architecture; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran
- A street view in Sultanabad (note: there are numerous locations named Sultanabad/Soultanabad in Iran. Considering the route, this is likely to be Arak (formerly called Soltan-Abad))., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref50; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Water; Children; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran
- A man working a carpet loom in Ensjidan (Anjudan), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref51; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Anjudan, Arak County, Markazi Province, Iran; Carpets/Rugs; Workers; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Individual Portraits; Buildings; Architecture
- A group portrait of a carpet weaving family taken in their home in Ibrahimabad (Ebrahimabad), a village on the road from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref52; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Architecture; Buildings; Houses; Workers; Children; Girls; Boys; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Ebrahimabad, Moshkabad, Arak County, Markazi Province, Iran
- A view of Ibrahimabad (Ebrahimabad), a carpet-weaving village on the way from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref53; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Buildings; Architecture; Carpets/Rugs; Streets/Roads; Deserts; Ebrahimabad, Moshkabad, Arak County, Markazi Province, Iran
- A group portrait of men from Malazer (Malayer) on their way to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref54; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Canes/Walking Sticks; Group Portraits; Deserts; Men; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Children; Mountains/Hills
- A caravanserai in Lalioun (possibly Lalan/Lālūn), a village on the way from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref55; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Hotels; Animals; Architecture; Buildings; Horses; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Canes/Walking Sticks; Swords/Knives; Weapons; Facial Hair; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran; Tehran, Iran
- A caravan on the road from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref56; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Horses; Men; Group Portraits; Mountains/Hills; Animals; Deserts; Regional/National Dress; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran
- A "European man" riding a horse on the road from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref57; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Hats; Horses; Men; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Animals; Deserts; Mountains/Hills; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran
- The road company guest house in Koom (Qum), on the road from Sultanabad to Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref58; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Men; Children; Hotels; Qum/Qom, Iran; Arāk (Sultanabad), Markazi Province, Iran
- A view of Toopkhaneh, a major town square and neighborhood in southern Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref59; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Tehran, Iran; Cannons; Architecture; Buildings; Street Lamps; Weapons
- A group portrait of several men and a woman in Tajreez, a neighborhood in Tehran near the Elburg (Alborz) Mountains in Tehran, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref60; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Mountains/Hills; Horses; Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Forest/Woodlands; Uniforms; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Women; Hats
- A post house in Mesreh, on the road from Tehran to Rescht (Rasht), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref61; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Houses; Hotels; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills
- Two carriages seen on the road from Tehran To Kasveen (Qazvin), Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref62; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Men; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Horses; Animals; Individual Portraits; Countryside/Rural
- A group portrait of men and children in a caravanserai in Tajreez, Iran., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref63; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Hotels; Men; Children; Boys; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair
- A house in Tabreez (Tabriz), Iran, 'built and occupied by a European.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref64; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Buildings; Architecture; Houses; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Workers; Uniforms; Tabriz, East Azerbaijan Province, Iran
- A carriage and a line of horses on the road from Tabreez (Tabriz), Iran, to Julfa (Caucasus), Azerbaijan., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref65; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iran; Caucasus; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Animals; Men; Fez/Tarboush; Regional/National Dress; Mountains/Hills; Streets/Roads; Group Portraits; Electricity; Facial Hair; Tabriz, East Azerbaijan Province, Iran
- A main street in Erivan (Yerevan) on the road from Tabreez (Tabriz), Iran, to Tiflis (Tbilisi), Georgia., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref66; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Tabriz, East Azerbaijan Province, Iran; Tbilisi, Georgia; Caucasus; Yerevan (Armenia); Signs/Signposts; Hotels; Streets/Roads; Horses; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; Hats; Transportation; Shops; Cyrillic Script; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Men; Buildings; Architecture; Street Lamps; Boys; Children; Uniforms
- A view of Tiflis (Tbilisi), Georgia, taken from the Hotel de Londres., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref67; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Tbilisi, Georgia; Caucasus; Hotels; Buildings; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Architecture; Churches; Religious Sites; Religious Crosses; Streets/Roads
- The Mushtahid (Mushthaid) Garden and the Kura River in Tiflis (Tbilisi), Georgia., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref68; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Tbilisi, Georgia; Caucasus; Gardens; Rivers; Parks; Water; Mountains/Hills
- The post house in Gudauri (Goudaour) on the Georgian Military Highway from Tiflis (Tbilisi), Georgia, to Vladikavkaz, Russia., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref69; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Tbilisi, Georgia; Russia; Streets/Roads; Military/Soldiers; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Horses; Animals; Street Lamps
- A view of the Bosphorus Strait near the entrance of the Golden Horn in Constantinople (Istanbul), Turkey., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref70; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Bosphorus; Istanbul, Turkey; Water; Mosques; Religious Sites; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Architecture; Mountains/Hills; Seas
- The Golden Horn in Constantinople (Istanbul), Turkey., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref71; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Bosphorus; Istanbul, Turkey; Seas; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Gardens; Parks; Buildings; Mountains/Hills
- A drawing room in Constantinople (Istanbul), Turkey., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref72; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Books; Hand Fans; Individual Portraits
- Buildings in Prinkipo (Büyükada), one of the Princes' islands near Constantinople (Istanbul), Turkey., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref73; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Buyukada, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings; Architecture; Forest/Woodlands; Mountains/Hills
- A view of Halki, one of the Princes' islands, taken from Prinkipo (Büyükada)., 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref74; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Mountains/Hills; Istanbul, Turkey; Buyukada, Istanbul, Turkey; Buildings; Water; Aegean Sea; Seas
- A blank page "in the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref75; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Iraq; Yerevan (Armenia); Istanbul, Turkey; Caucasus; Tbilisi, Georgia
- A blank page "in the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref76; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Iraq; Yerevan (Armenia); Caucasus; Tbilisi, Georgia; Istanbul, Turkey
- The inside back cover of the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref77; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); Thomson, John; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iran; Iraq; Istanbul, Turkey; Yerevan (Armenia); Caucasus; Tbilisi, Georgia
- The back cover of the album 'Photographs of Iran, Iraq, Caucasus, and Turkey.', 1890-1891; AD_MC_061_ref78; Hotz, A. P. H. (Albertus Paulus Hermanus); 1 Photographic Prints (Box 061)